monash.edu.au 2018-12-16

# Monash University Websites Privacy Statement - Monash University

Monash University is subject to the **Privacy and Data Protection Act 2014 (Victoria)**. The University is committed to protecting your privacy. The following sets out how the University will deal with personal information recorded through the use of its web sites.

## 1\. Collection of Information

### Information automatically logged

The University may make a record of your visit and log any of the following information for statistical and business purposes- the user's address, the user's domain name, IP address, the date and time of the visit, the pages accessed and documents downloaded, the previous site visited and the type of browser used. Identification of the user may also be requested and logged.

Information about your visit to a University website may also be logged by Nielsen//Netratings Pty Ltd to provide the University with de-identified statistical analysis about users' online experiences and trends.

If you are not a Monash student or a University staff member and you send us a message, the University will record your e-mail address.

### Security information

University sites have security measures in place against the loss, misuse and alteration of information as defined in the University's IT Security Policy.

A login name and password are required to visit secure areas. Before personal information (such as examination results) is published on the site, visitors are required to enter their student or staff number as well. This is to ensure that the information is displayed only to the intended person. You should ensure that your password is kept securely and cannot be discovered by anyone else.

### Cookies

A cookie is a small message given to your web browser by our web server. The browser stores the message in a text file and the message is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. It is possible to disable the acceptance of cookies by your web browser. However, doing so may restrict your ability to access some web pages.

Some University sites are access restricted. These sites may use cookies to deliver content specific to your interest. Cookies may also be used for authentication purposes and to improve security during a visitor's session online.

Cookies may store the following information: session (numbered key) and duration. A numbered key is a unique server-generated number used to track your current session. The session key can be linked back to a user's login identification.

Unique identifiers (such as login name and password) are collected from web site visitors to verify a user's identity and for use as account numbers in our record system.

Unique identifiers are also used to access stored information about a visitor's preferences to enable the dynamic display of the site according to your preferences when you return.

### On-line surveys

All research surveys conducted online by University staff and /or students which involve the collection of personal information, will have received approval from the University's Committee for Human Ethics in Research. A survey might ask visitors for unique identifiers (such as login information).

### Enrolment and registration forms

If personal information is collected via a website and held, every effort will be made to ensure that this is done by sufficiently secure means.

A student may elect to enroll in person rather than providing personal information to the University via a website.

For certain applications, our site's enrolment and registration forms require users to give contact information (like name and e-mail address) and unique identifiers (like login identification and student number).

### External links

Some University sites contain links to other sites. The University is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites.

## 2\. Use of Personal Information

Personal information you supply online will be used by the University staff in conducting the business of the University. Such uses include matters related to student administration, provision of services and the dissemination of information to staff, prospective and current students and remaining in contact with graduates. The University may also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with a server and to administer a web site. Your IP address is sometimes used to set up individual sessions to provide secure logins.

## 3\. Disclosure of personal information

The University will not disclose personal information concerning you to parties outside the University. However, staff email addresses will be made available in accordance with Monash's **External Access to Staff Contact Details Policy**.

### Public forums

Some University sites may have chat rooms, forums, on-line teaching environments, message boards and or/news groups available to their users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

## 4\. Data quality/access

The University will always try to maintain accurate, complete and up-to-date information regarding staff and students. If you think that your personal information retained by the University requires changing please contact Student Services or HR Services as appropriate.

## 5\. More information

For more information, view the [University's Privacy Procedure](http://www.privacy.monash.edu/procedure/).
